Srivas Chennu

srivaschennu.github.io +44 7828 90 66 92 srivas@gmail.com



Profile

I specialise in translating the latest machine learning and statistical inference methods into scalable real-world applications in industry and academia. I have 14+ years of R&D experience, and a background in computer science. My research has been featured by the BBC, Wired Magazine, New Scientist and Discovery Channel. I have worked as a consultant and as a software engineer.

Employment

Senior Machine Learning Scientist	Apple, UK	2019-present	
Developed large-scale deep learning and gradient boosting models for behavioural prediction			
Designed and deployed adaptive reinforcement learning, improving user engagement and revenue			
Assistant Professor	University of Kent, UK	2016-2019	
Led health care AI project to predict biomarkers of consciousness using time series analysis			
Visiting Researcher	The Alan Turing Institute, UK	2018	
Senior Research Associate	University of Cambridge, UK	2010-2016	
Developed statistical, ML and time series models for healthcare technology applications in neurology			
Research Assistant	Technical University of Hamburg	2005	
Developed convex optimisation and linear programming solutions for industrial applications			
Member of Technical Staff	Oracle Corporation, India	2002-2004	
• Software engineer in the Oracle Reports team, a part of Oracle's Internet Application Server platform			

Consulting

DataTiger (Marketing optimisation startup acquired by Apple)

2018

• Applied ensemble machine learning for forecasting dynamics of customer behaviour

Rsrchxchange (FinTech startup)

2017

- Built neural network-based NLP model for content similarity analysis of financial research reports
- Developed latent factor models with Apache Spark to build financial research recommender models

Research

- Co-author of 50+ peer-reviewed publications in academic journals; h-index of 26 (as of 2022)
- · On deep learning, reinforcement learning, computational neuroscience and Bayesian inference

Education

PhD in Computer Science	University of Kent, Canterbury, UK	2006-2009
MSc in Information and Communication Systems	Hamburg University of Technology Hamburg, Germany	2004-2006
BEng in Computer Science and Engineering	Visveswaraiah Technological University Bangalore, India	1998-2002

Skills

- Big Data Modelling, Machine Learning
- Parametric, Non-parametric and Bayesian Statistics
- Signal Processing and Time Series Analysis
- Graph Theory and Network Analysis
- **Tools**: tensorflow, pytorch, scipy, pandas, pyspark
- Deep Neural Networks
- Applied Artificial Intelligence
- Computer Networking and Security
- Operating Systems
- Languages: Python, JAVA, C++, C